Preliminary Inventory to the Charles T. R. Bohannan Papers 1915-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
- Part II
  - Vietnam material (psychological operations, counter insurgency, Viet Cong propaganda, etc.) (Box 34)
    - 18., 1964-1965
      - Concept of Rural Reconstruction, Definitions and Procedures, 1965 May
      - Vietnam Special Course Orientation Branch
      - Summary of Principal Events in Vietnam, 1920-1957, 1965 July
    - 19. Team notes/Inter-office memoranda and correspondence, 1965 August-1966 January
      - Activities Report, Mark Huss, 1965 August 12-19
      - Office memo from R. Phillips/Actions for Ky, 1965 September
      - Quote from Abraham Lincoln
      - Memo: Conversation with Ambassador Lodge
      - Draft memo: Making Low-Level Advisors Effective (dynamite - handle with care)
      - Memo for the record: Bohannan (two)
      - Private visit, 3 Republican Congressmen
      - Internal frictions; Maik contract; Personal, 1965 October-November
      - Eyes Only EGL; Bohannan re internal friction; letter from Tris
      - To Team Members/Joe Baker/Ideas (stack of memos for the record, Bohannan, Slobo), 1965 October
      - Problems of Government: Memo, (stack of memos, Bohannan), 1965 November
      - Problems in Vietnam (stack of memos, Bohannan, 1965 December)
      - To SLO staff from EGL, December
      - Miscellaneous papers
        - List of Files
        - Memo Chieu Hoi/Cooper, 1965 August
        - Questions for EGL, 1965 October
        - Ideas requested, 1965 November
        - Discussion paper/Draft
      - Karrick to SLO Team members, 1966 January
      - Study Outline proposed/Pacification and Development
      - A Catalyzing Team for Vietnam/Draft, Bohannan
    - 20. Personal correspondence and reports, USOM/Vietnam, "Huwag" (i.e. "keep out"), 1963
      - Letter to Brig. Gen. York, 1963 January
      - Memo to Geriner: Tactics and Techniques of C.I., Review of, 1963 February
      - Psychological War Special Course on Chieu Hoi, 1963 February-March
      - Memo to Maj. Barbera re ECCOI Contract problems, 1963 February
      - Visit with Gen. Oai, et al., 1963 February
      - Memo re Project for Regrouping Lislead Resistants
      - Speech by Minister of Civic Action
      - Memo to Phillips: Chieu Hoi, View of Hieu, 1963 May
      - Letter to Praeger ordering 40 copies of book (Bohannan/Val CG Ops)
      - Letter from Oai to Bohannan: thanks for book
      - Letter from Vic Hugo to Rufe
      - Memo re Chieu Hoi: Support Committee Meeting
      - Draft: Brent to Ambassador re RVNAF Personnel, Politics and CI Effort with Draft from Phillips, 1963 July
      - Phillips to Nolting re Bombs, Rockets, Shells, Popular Support and the US? Interest
      - Memo for the record: Conversation with Gen. Mai Huu Xuan, 1963 November
      - Prov Rep Report: Long An Province for, 1963 November
      - Memo for Mike re The Way of the War
      - Memo of Bohannan re Gen. Don and the Philippines
      - Letter from Mike Dunn, through Bohannan, to Cleve, re Chieu Hoi/Psychological War, 1964 January 6
      - To: Members of Psychological Operations Committee from Working Group re the American Presence in Vietnam, 1964 February
      - Letter to Bohannan from Philippines Anti-Communist Movement/Tante; Gen. Santos to Mac Peralta; C. Cao to SND re Operation Pagasa
    - 21. Correspondence, memoranda, miscellaneous papers re Vietnam, 1963-1965
      - Letter to Felix Jabillo re Philippines Constabulary Manual of, 1915, 1963 August
      - Letter to Mike Dunn re Scarnes story, 1963 October
      - Notes: Interesting points at Junta Press Conference, Vietnam Army Forces Headquarters, 1963 November 6
      - Conversation with Le Van Thai, 1963 November 10
      - Task Force Freedom
      - Memo for Mag Nguyen Thanh Luong re Publicity for an ARVN Civic Action Project, 1963 November 21
      - Memo for Gen Le Van Kim, 1963 November 27
      - Pencil notes to Bohannan from Cleve
      - Memo: The Sad State of Affairs, 1963 December 7
      - Letter to Col. William Law, Laos, from Bohannan, re successful counter insurgency, 1963 December
      - Strategy of counter insurgency: Concept, Organization, Application, Conclusion with enclosures (Bohannan)
      - Letter to Frisco from Bohannan, 1963 December
      - Letter to Magin Sn Juan from Bohannan, 1963 December
      - Letter to Bohannan from Magin, 1963 December
      - Memo for Mike Dunn: Continuing to Lose the War
      - Letter to Nguyen Mi Thai from Rufe (cc to Bohannan)
      - Memo to Len Maynard from R. Holbrooke, USOM/Ba Xuyen, by Bohannan, 1964 January 8
      - Notes from meeting Soc Trang, (campaign plan), 1964 January 8
      - Note: Memo to Bohannan from Cleve, 1964 January 9
      - Memo for the record: Personalities and Roles in the New MRC, 1964 January 31
      - By Bohannan: A few notes on Situation and Terrain, (probably to EGL), 1964 January
      - Memo to Mike Dunn from Bohannan, re Mostly Psychological, 1964 January
      - Letter to Bohannan from Ed Navarro with Galang address and Veteran rehabilitation contact, 1964 January
      - Informal, Unofficial Memo: To Lt. Col. Cushman from Bohannan re Operations Plan Draft, 21st Infantry, 1964 January 15
      - Memo for the record: Hamlet Militia Leader Training, by Bohannan, 1964 March 10
      - Notes: Required Actions if War is to be Won, (Bohannan), 1964 November 18
      - Memo for the record: Evacuation of American Dependants, 1964 February 18
      - Pacification: A Few Do's and Don'ts
      - Suggested Guidelines for Ambassador's Approach to President Diem
      - Halberstam cable to New York Times (5 pages)
      - Critique of MACV's reply to Halberstam story, (draft, 4 pages)
      - Provincial intelligence
      - Memo to Mike Dunn re fact finding, 1963 December 9
      - Memo Quang Ngai, (almost illegible), 1963 December 9
      - Comments on Planning
      - Memo to Bohannan from Geo Melvin re Special Cambodian Border Force Supplement, 1963 December 17
      - Memo re Leadership Motivation, by Wilbur Wilson, 1964 February 25
      - Sr. Advisors Estimate of the Situation re Indigenous Leadership Motivation
      - Memo to Sol Silver from Bohannan, re Pay of Armed Forces, 1964 February 17
      - Memo for the record re Bohannan's relations with Eastern Construction Company, 1964 March 16
      - Notes to Bohannan from ?, 1964 February
      - More notes to Bohannan, 1964 March
      - Letter to Bohannan from Rick Galang, 1964 April 14
      - A Note from Stan Atkinson to Ed Lansdale
      - Correspondence between Bohannan and Ed Lansdale regarding General Xuan
      - Letter to Ambassador Lodge from Atkinson re detention of Mai Huu Xuan, 1964 April 17
      - Typed copy of a message from Cleveland to Bohannan, dated, 1964 May
      - Copy of letter dated to? from? (Bravo? almost illegible), 1964 September 1
      - Letter to Len Maynard from Bohannan (in Kensington, Md), 1964 August
      - Excerpt re withdrawal of support from Father Hoa; from TTSquare, 1964 September 1
      - Official Memo to Maynard from Gosho re Chieu Hoi Task Force: Charles T. R. Bohannan not needed, 1965 June 21
      - Letter to Bohannan from Mark ("somebody torpedoed Charles T. R. Bohannan's expeditionary force to rescue Chieu Hoi"), 1965 July
      - Cable to Bohannan from Carabao, 1964?
      - Invitation to Bohannan for dinner with Tran-Van-An, Minister for Open Arms, 1965 April
      - Letter to Bohannan from Len Maynard re Chieu Hoi, 1965 July
      - Letter to Bohannan from Bravo, 1965 January
      - Letter to Bohannan from Bravo re Chieu Hoi, 1965 July
      - Letter to Bohannan from Hickerson, Ft. Belvoir, Va, re weapons, 1965 August
    - 22. /
    - 23. Inter-Agency Task Force Report on Chieu Hoi Program, 1965 August (Box 36)
    - 24. Photos: Community Development Advisor Pete Guillermo in Khan Hoa, 1969-1970
  - Philippines material
    - 25. Power Moves Involved in the Overthrow of an Unfriendly Government [Philippines]
    - 26. Bulletin Today (Philippines), 1985 June 14
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1947-1964 (Box 36)
  Scope and Contents note
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government. Includes some records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover
  - 2011 June release of records, 1947-1964 (Box 36)
    Articles and memo relating to the situation in Vietnam, 1962-1964, and letter from the American Embassy in Manila, Philippines, 1947. The articles are contained in the notebook with "Articles III HUAG" on the spine and "VN 11" noted on the cover, with titles indicated below
    - 1. Working Draft: Political Evolution in South Vietnam, H. J. Gaffney, Jr., Policy Planning Staff/ISA, 1964 October
    - 2. Notes on Current US Problem Areas in Vietnam, Chas. J. Zwick, Chas. Cooper, Hans Heyman, Richard Moorsteen, 1964 August
    - 3. Memo: Current Breakdown of GVN Pol. Civic Action Programs for Forestal, signed by William E. Colby
    - 4. Sixth Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy: The Evolution of Counter Insurgency Strategy, The case of Vietnam, pages, by Col. Richard M. Lee, USA, 1964 June 30, 69
    - 5. The United States and France in Vietnam: A Comparison Research Memo, RFE-34, from Thomas L. Hughes, 1964 May 21
    - 6. Chronology of United States-Vietnam Relations, 1949-1964
    - 7. Obstacles to Mass Communication in Vietnam, USJS/WG Saigon, 1963 December
- "Vietnam" 16mm motion picture film, 150 feet (Film shelf Film shelf)